Mayowa Odebode

Adept front-end developer focusing on javascript mobile-first developments and web applications/services. After success with WordPress development and 3 years of front-end experience, I am eager to continue expanding my javascript knowledge into perfecting accessibility and responsive design.

Kigali, Rwanda (250) 784-928-922 itopaodebode@gmail.com

Portfolio:

https://mayowa-odebode.netlifv.app/

EXPERIENCE

SAFIRUN, Kigali, Rwanda — Frontend Developer

OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

 Designed & developed in-house analytic interfaces to track & manage orders and services on the SAFIRUN mobile application.

 Rebuilt 3 years old SAFIRUN Website and web app version for the SAFIRUN mobile app

 Designed and implemented web applications along with 3rd-party software integrations as a web team liaison for all interdepartmental and customer-facing projects.

 Designed and developed an e-charging station website & a ride-hailing service website.

 Designed and developed web platforms for All-Electric Vehicle (EV) ride-hailing service.

XIDIAN TECH - SaaS, Kigali, Rwanda. — *Lead Frontend Engineer*

APR 2021 - OCT 2021

- Determining structure and design of web pages
- Optimizing the user experience by ensuring the technical feasibility of UI/UX Designs
- Developing and maintaining the user interface.
- Implementing design on mobile websites.
- Creating tools that improve site interaction regardless of the browser.
- Adopting and utilizing SEO best practices.
- Testing and fixing for usability.

WOUESSI - Digital Intelligence Company, Kigali, Rwanda. — Web Developer / WordPress Developer

JAN 2021 - MAR 2021

- Setting up development environments
- Designing and implementing new features and functionality
- Establishing and guiding the website's architecture
- Ensuring high-performance and availability, and managing all technical aspects of the CMS
- Helping formulate an effective, responsive design and turning it into a working theme.
- Utilizing a deep understanding of the WP library and other standard practices to produce great WP-based products.

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

Javascript

Tailwind CSS

WordPress

GIT/Github

LANGUAGES

English (Fluent), Yoruba, Pidgin

EDUCATION

Middlesex University, London, UK. — BSc (Hons) Information Technology &Business information systems

GRADUATED - August 2016

PROJECT(S)

thrift.rw: a web platform where users get to sell off some of their items that they no longer need or use but is still in great shape. ONGOING